A Guide to the 1952 All America City Award Records 1952-1954
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
A Guide to the 1952 All America City Award Records
Roanoke Public Libraries
2014.04.18
1 legal record storage box
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
M. Carl Andrews
Biographical Note
The 1952 All-America City Award Records were created and or collected and compiled by M. Carl Andrews, Editor of the Roanoke Times and World News. Items include correspondence to and from Andrews in reference to the award and nomination, photographs, news clippings, and other related documents. M. Carl Andrews (Oct. 24, 1904 – June 9, 1994), a native of Logan County, Oklahoma, grew up in Newport News and came to Roanoke in 1929 to join the staff of The Roanoke Times. He was a news editor from 1929 until 1935, at which point he was assigned to cover the Franklin County liquor conspiracy trial. He was made city editor of the Times in 1937 and held that post until he left for service in World War II in 1943. Upon his return in 1946, he was named editorial page editor of The World-News, a position he held until his retirement November 1, 1969. Andrews was actively involved in numerous civic and professional organizations, serving as Chairman of the Mill Mountain Development Committee, co-Chair of the committee organizing America's Bicentennial Celebration, and a founding member of the National Conference of Editorial Writers.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of one legal-size document storage case, consisting of eighteen file folders. Items include: personal and professional correspondence, photographs, press releases, radio transcript, several periodical containing related articles, news clippings, banquet menu, and an address by George Gallup. The dates of materials in the collection are between the years of 1952 and 1954, with a separate file for all documents related to attempts at the award in the 1960s. Some highlights of the collection include letters to Andrews from Congressman Richard Poff and the editorial staff of Look magazine. One 8”x10” photograph shows of Andrews, City Manager Arthur Owens, and Hunter Akers posing in front of a billboard erected to honor the City of Roanoke for its win. 5 4”x6” photographs of awards banquet attendees and a menu from the banquet should also be noted.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by document type with documents arranged in each folder chronologically.
Contents List
- Address by George Gallup at the All American City Awards Banquet at the Hotel Roanoke 19530128 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence from M. Carl Andrews 1953-1954 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from the City of Roanoke. 1952-1953 (Folder 3)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from Congressman Richard Poff. 1953 (Folder 4)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from Jane Douglas of Look Magazine. 1952 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from various individuals. 1953-1954 (Folder 6)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from the National Municipal League. 1953-1954 (Folder 7)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews, telegrams. 1952-1953 (Folder 8)
- Correspondence to M. Carl Andrews from Senator A. Willis Robertson. 1953 (Folder 9)
- Menu from awards banquet. 19530128 (Folder 10)
- News clippings 1952-1954 (Folder 11)
- Other efforts toward All-America nominations in the 1960s. 1960-1967 (Folder 12)
- Packet of items compiled from 1952-1953 win, created October 2012 for 2012 All-America City Award win. 2012 (Folder 13)
- Photographs 19530128 (Folder 14)
- Press Releases 1952-1953 (Folder 15)
- Publication - Look Magazine 19530210 (Folder 16)
- Publication - Virginia Club Woman 19530401 (Folder 17)
- Publication - Virginia Veteran 19530601 (Folder 18)
- Transcript of Citizens at Work radio show. 19540627 (Folder 19)